Claude is now doing 26% of Anthropic's
own research. That's up from under 1%
back in February. Uh they have 30,000 AI
agents all running experiments and
writing code and building the next
claude. But here's the problem. Every AI
lab is training on the same internet,
the same threads, the same answers. And
that internet is now flooded with AI
slop. Models are training on models.
It's a photocopy of a photocopy. in
every generation gets a little
blurriier. So, the labs are desperate
for the one thing that money can't
print. Fresh original human thought.
Real people arguing, reviewing, coding,
explaining why they believe something.
And there's a finite amount of it. 10
days ago, a federal judge told one AI
lab that it can't just scrape for free
anymore. The pile of human arguments
just got a legal price tag. Today on
Dumb Money, AI is running out of human
data. Here's the trade.
This is Dumb Money Live.
>> Hey there, Dave here along with Chris
and Jordan. We are Dumb Money. Welcome
to Dumb Money Live. Uh do me a quick
favor if you don't mind. Smash the like
button. A real human clicking on it as
of today is still apparently uh valuable
training data. So, good morning Chris
Jordan. Uh we know Chris, you have been
building a big position in a company
that is sitting on perhaps the largest
pile of human arguments on the internet.
And you say you might be going bigger.
Is that right?
>> Yeah. I mean, I I wouldn't say that I
have like
that meaningful of a position at this
moment. It's it's it's moderate, right?
Um I mean, we all know Wall Street's
paying for these machines, right? I want
to know like where the human signal is
that the machines cannot manufacture,
right? Like,
>> yeah,
>> I think that's what this is all about.
Um,
you know, I if you look at every uh
piece of research in the AI space, it
becomes pretty evident that
we're going to get into some kind of
issue here in the next few years with,
you know, just AI uh a AI uh data um
becoming too large of a piece of of the
source data. Right. And and you just
we're not going to have enough actual
human data and and and the and it just
starts to build on itself. And then I
I've been reading all these reports and
you never know what's true, right?
>> Well, and that's the biggest problem
now. We don't know it's true because we
have the entire human history of
information and the AI bots now have
access to more and more of it and
they're processing more and more of it
but they're spitting out more
information faster than humans ever
created it and it is it is a problem.
Yeah,
there's a thesis out there that the the
data get starts to get really bad if it
just becomes replicated over and over
again with with with AI data, right? I I
don't even know if any of this is real.
This is the problem. Like every people
are throwing out papers, opinions,
thesis. Like I we're in unchartered
territory. I don't know if anyone can
say for con with conviction exactly how
this all plays out, but it seems like at
a minimum buying or paying a lot of
money to lock in one of the very few
last remaining
truly
uh fresh high signal
uh permissioned human data is a
no-brainer for all these big labs,
right? like how do they not do whatever
it takes to acquire
that? I I I just don't see very many
scenarios where they just blow that off
because if you look at Google, Google
inherently has the data advantage,
right? With video data, they have a huge
advantage even with email data. Um, if
you start to look at, you know, a couple
the other labs, they don't necessarily
have as much uh owned data. They have to
go out and license it, right?
>> Yeah. With Yeah. I mean, with email data
though, do they have the rights to to
use that to train their models? Is that
in the terms and conditions within the
email client? I haven't looked at that
one specifically. Now, X uh AI probably
has a pretty good advantage in being
able to use, you know, X.com data.
>> Do Do you think do you think X AI is
that great of a data source, though?
Like
>> I think it's good. So, look, I mean, so
I was listening to a um a podcast where
the where they're interviewing the CEO
of Reddit, and he thinks that obviously
the the best thing about their data is
that it's highly human. It's arguments
back and forth. Sometimes when we think
about AI, we think about we just want
the answer. But sometimes it's not about
the answer. Sometimes it's about
differences, opinions. It's about the
argument. It's about different use
cases. It's about um it's about the
journey of trying to figure out what's
the best situation for yourself, right?
And I think that you know you get that
really good in Reddit. Um and you get
that to a certain extent in X also,
right? Because there is a back and forth
and there's a way for people to argue
about different topics.
>> I I guess to some extent on X, but I
think it would be highly limited to
maybe some maybe technology, politics,
finance. I just don't see a lot.
>> Yeah, I think you get you get a more
broad um
you get broader topics in Reddit, right?
Um
>> yeah, I mean this is where you go back
to, you know, something like YouTube and
and you do actually get a lot a pretty
good breath of data on YouTube.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh which makes you go back and think,
wow, I can't wait to see what these
future releases of Gemini look like.
There are some rumors out there that
this next Gemini release is
earthshattering, right?
>> Traditionally, Google or Google and
YouTube is a place that people go to
create original things, but more and
more YouTube is starting to fill up with
videos that were created by AI. And we
know that X, I don't know if anyone
noticed, but my uh my profile on X
started posting uh like a week ago. Do
you think I wrote those posts? Do you
think I have any reason to want to get
on X? And like Chris, you're an ex-ce
celebrity. You have a reason to be on
there. I don't have a reason to be on X
and I don't want to be a YouTube or
exceed. I don't I don't want to be in
their their program that you get paid
for posting things. That just that just
doesn't interest me. But I put my AI
agents on it and they started like
watching episodes of what we do here and
finding things that they think that they
might that I might have an opinion on.
anyone who's writing my uh post for me.
>> Yeah. Well, I think that's some strength
of X, right? Is that things are topical
and timely things that are
>> and and I like highly topical right now,
right? And be a little bit more broad.
>> A lot of people are posting original
content on X most of
>> another thing that's topical and timely
right now given what we're talking about
is I just noticed I had the I had, you
know, stock chart for Reddit up and it
has plunged. It has plunged and so I
used X to figure out why is Reddit
plunging right now. Do you know?
>> Well, yeah, they they've had a revenue
growth slowdown, Jordan. And
>> so kind of Yeah. And so, but that has
nothing to do with why it plunged right
now. Um, so the reason it plunged right
now is that Meta just announced a
competitor to Reddit.
>> Oh, how did I miss that?
>> It just happened like literally this
second. So unless you were trying to
figure it out this second, then you
wouldn't have caught it.
>> Wow. Wow, dude. That's Hold on. That's
crazy. What? What? They
>> I don't know any more information.
That's all I know.
>> Let me take a look here. Oh, you're
right. Cuz Reddit was up and look at it.
>> Yeah, it was up and now it's slightly
down. Not a big deal, but
>> wow.
Um, what is this comp? So, what does
that look like? Why? I don't think I
don't see Meta being in a position of
trust or really having the connection
points to be able to compete with
Reddit. That doesn't make any sense to
me at all.
>> Yeah. The the the weird thing about
Facebook and Meta is that the way that
you organize yourself tends to be around
personal relationships. And the way that
you tend to organize yourself in Reddit
is around shared interests. And so
unless they're going to totally change
that model or have some forum where you
do all those things, it seems like kind
of a slow start for meta.
>> Dude, Jordan, they've already failed
this with threads. Okay. People do not
want to dig into a meta platform to
share their insights and deep opinions.
It's I don't see that working at all.
Absolutely not. Nobody trusts Meta.
>> Yeah.
>> To want to sh like No, they just don't
they don't like them enough. Right. Like
>> I don't think it has anything to do with
like. I think it has to do with with
where you know um just the just the way
that you've already organized yourself
within their platforms doesn't make
sense for this topical type of um
discuss. The problem is they're trying
to fix some something that's not broken.
Reddit's not broken in that way.
>> Reddit's not broken at all. Reddit
actually has done a fantastic job um
with their user experience and their
value proposition.
>> The one knock against Reddit right now
is that they are also a victim of AI
content infiltrating the platform.
>> Well, they're trying to not be. That's
one of the things that they're trying to
trying to make sure doesn't happen
because they want that novelty. They
want to make sure that it's a human
connection place to go and discuss
topics
which also on the other hand makes it
very valuable for AI training.
Guys, I listen. If you just play out
some scenarios over the next five years,
it seems inevitable that the world is
going to become consumed by AI data and
to some extent AI slop. And there will
be a large percentage of humans that
will desire a platform where they can
engage with other humans and they could
also get the opinions of other humans. I
don't even care if those opinions are
inferior to what they can get from AI.
There will be a large audience for that.
And with Reddit being the number one
destination in the world for human
interactions and content,
I'm just bewildered that this company is
not getting more eyeballs on it right
now from the investor community. even
before you get into the fact that their
data should theoretically
continue to grow in value as a training
tool for AI. Even if you don't count
that, um it just seems that inevitable
over the next five years that it will
become a really precious platform if
they do their job right, if they if they
continue to execute. Now, I know their
growth rate has slowed.
>> Their growth rate has slowed. I think
they only had 7% user growth um as of
the last reporting cycle. Um
>> but Jordan,
>> which is good,
>> Jordan, that's also that's also natural,
right? Um
>> I I think that that's a natural place to
be. At the same time that you're saying
their user growth has slowed, they came
out and said that 5% of all the content
that's ever been written on Reddit has
been written in the last quarter. So it
seems like the engagement is up
meaningfully unless that content is AI
content. And I try to figure that out. I
can't figure out how much if any of that
lift
>> in content being written is due to AI.
So that that's still an open question.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And somebody just made a
comment. The entire corpus of Reddit
data is available
um on the dark web. Um they actually so
this is the interesting thing about um
Reddit is that they make their data
available for free to researchers. Um
and not a lot of companies do that. They
just want to make sure that if you're
using the data for commercial purposes
that you pay and so they want
>> um you know they want these people that
are using it for training to pay. And um
that tends to be what's going on right
now. I'm not 100% sure that everybody
that's doing AI training, especially if
you're outside the United States, are
you paying Reddit? I I don't know. Um
but
>> yeah, but
>> yeah, there are ways around that. Um
>> I I'm not super concerned there because
if you're one of the top u model
companies, you obviously are going to
have to pay. You can't just sneak in.
You can't just sneak in and steal it,
right?
>> Open AI. If you're one of these like
blue chip model companies and Yeah. you
got you have to pay.
>> Yeah. I So I I I see them eventually
having dozens and dozens and dozens of
massively large uh you know tech
entities that are going to be paying
them for their data. And I just
>> have a really difficult time seeing how
the cost of that data doesn't go up
exponentially over the next few years as
these deals expire and they get renewed.
How is that not a big story every time
we see a Reddit renewal, you know,
completing at a meaningfully higher rate
than where it was previously and they
just continue to raise the bar for that?
There's just not a lot of alternatives.
That's the question.
>> Look, I mean, so some of the
alternatives have been that, you know,
these companies are, you know, buying
old books and doing all these things and
trying to figure out how to get as much
data in them as possible. And I think
that's great. Um, but what it doesn't do
is get up-to-date information, right?
some of the old books that they're
getting, you know, great. Maybe it helps
the language model learn how to
communicate better, but how to speak and
maybe some like other information, but
if you want to know, you know, anything
about the latest concert or like how,
you know, what should I wear to
whatever, what where are people going
out and any any type of timely topical
piece of information, you're going to
need, you know, like an X or a Reddit
where people are talking about
>> or Tik Tok.
>> Yeah. Any any type of current
information. Yeah. Yeah. Every model
that's chasing basically human judgment,
right? They have to pay for it. Yeah.
>> So,
it just seems I love the I love the
riskreward of Reddit. I I know that in
the short run it's going to be very
difficult to kind of figure out what
happens to Reddit week by week. Like
look what happened today with the meta
news, right? Well, if you uh if you were
playing it if you were playing this
swing trade and you got in on the uh two
and a half percent micro the flash
crash, you would have already recovered
by half now.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I was already kind of thinking
that because I was like, give me a
break, you know, like it's it doesn't
make any sense to me.
>> I also think give me a break on the
metaphor forum. I I don't see that being
successful. They've they've failed too
many times at trying to branch out into
new
>> It seems like everybody has tried to at
one point or another have the next
Reddit. Uh
>> yeah,
>> 20 years ago, Yahoo had something called
Yahoo Answers that they were trying to
be a platform where people would ask
questions and and do answer. Google has
one like everybody has this forum. The
ones that stuck around were Reddit and
then that uh that Stack Exchange
Overflow. What was a stack
>> stack overflow and stack overflow is
interesting but it's
>> it tends to be more um technical
>> tech nerds. Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's a tech nerd type destination
and it's figure out but it's a very it's
a very specific place to go to where
Reddit is a lot more broad.
>> Yeah. And Reddit's a great place because
people do go there to argue and to share
their thoughts. It's like I don't I
don't spend time in Reddit, but when I
need a reliable source, I'm I'm telling
my AI to go look at Reddit, and that's
what it's sourcing for me.
>> Yeah. Well, here's the thing. It just
unites nerds from around the planet on
whatever their nerd topic is. Is it
watches? Is it lawns? Is it, you know,
any type of thing that people could be,
>> you know, their nerd out over? There is
a place on Reddit for them to
>> Absolutely. And there there's a very
active credit card points uh network on
Reddit. There's all there's a subreddit
for everything.
>> Listen guys, I think it's an incredibly
valuable
um data company. Like it's just it's
absolutely incredible here that that
people aren't seeing it. I do think
there's an interesting trade to run a
scenario analysis on and just to have a
prepared mind on. And I I don't think
it's a trade anyone's thinking about on
this. I think there is uh a likelihood
that Reddit is going to either at some
point in the future get acquired or
announce one or more major new licensing
deals at rates that are significantly
higher than they are today. And I think
there will be a tiny arbitrage window
when those announcements potentially
happen. if they do
to trade a couple the other stocks that
would move in alignment with Reddit,
right, that have similar types of data.
Well, maybe not similar types of data,
but data that would be valued in a
similar way. Um, yeah, I mean, Stack
Overflow is one example, but how about
Yelp, right?
>> Yeah. I mean, you still need a real
person, okay, to actually tell you if
the food is good or bad at a restaurant.
Now, I hate Yelp. I cannot stand the
company. I would not want to own the
company.
>> I don't like the company and I also
don't like their data. Like, I don't I
don't think the people on Yelp are
reliable. I think that Google reviews
are much better for restaurants and for
any type of business than what you're
>> Dave, you're right. Which is why I have
zero interest in owning Yelp except for
a 5 to 10 minute trade if and when there
would ever be an announcement of an
acquisition offer for Reddit or some
major licensing deal that shoots Reddit
stock up. I think there will be some
arbitrage window to go trade Yelp uh and
to go trade a shutter stock as well,
right? Like for photography. So these
are just some other companies that
should react in a smaller but similar
matter
if if Reddit does kind of get that bid
at some point. So that just
>> if any one of them get some sort of
takeover target then the rest of them
are going to pop just on that news.
>> You Jordan, you're correct but I do
think there's going to be a multi-minute
arbitrage window when that happens.
>> Yeah.
>> So
>> yeah.
>> Anyway, it's it's kind of a weird trade
but these are thing I just run all these
scenarios and I like to have a prepared
mind. I like to have them ready to go so
that let's say let's say it's a 20%
chance that that Reddit gets acquired,
right? like it doesn't matter that that
that's a 20% chance that one of these
trades will will will kind of come into
uh becoming viable and I think it's a
really easy trade. So that's something
I'm thinking about as well. I bought
more Reddit just now by the way a few
minutes ago when you guys were talking
>> and quite honestly
>> a relatively small position for you.
>> I I would say a not not small but but
moderate. Not it's certainly not like a
top five position top
>> medium. It's just It's just outside.
It's just outside. Um, by the way, did
you see bloom today? Yesterday.
>> That's I was going to bring that up.
>> It's been weird. It's go It goes up 12%.
It drops like 12% and then it goes up
12%.
>> Yeah. I mean, they're they're expanding
their factory, their their fuel. So, I
mean, listen, we know Bloom. We know
what's real.
>> The market
stock every time it drops like that
>> down 9% up 13%. It's a wild ride for
sure.
>> Yeah, I I just I should have bought more
when it dropped again. I was just kind
of over not wanting to overly trade this
last week.
>> Yeah.
>> I want to know what's going through your
guys' mind just psychologically with
this AI trade because I'm assuming that
every investor in the world is going
through something similar to what I'm
going through right now. I've been
trading for decades and I have never
with the exception of a small period of
time during COVID, I have never
experienced a market where there is so
much uncertainty. If you look at just
the last week and you look at the next
few weeks of what's about to happen,
we're going to get Gemini. We have new
models. We have
>> AI delaying their 6.1 model because it's
dangerous. We have the AI companies
themselves saying, "Hey, government,
please step in and stop us." Why we
can't just stop ourselves, I don't know,
but liability. They just want the
government to say you these are the
rules and as long as they follow those
rules, it's fine.
>> Well, you have Sam Alman coming out
talking about, you know, AIC scaping,
you know, doing this is there are so
many unknowns and, you know, the market
completely hates unknowns. I' I've never
been loans. I think the biggest problem
that you have right now with the market
and why you see things skipping, why you
see Bloom swinging 10% a day is that
is that we do have a lot of confidence
in AI, right? I mean, people talk about
a bubble and there is a bubble, but it
has nothing to do with AI. Maybe a
little bit, um, but it's a debt bubble,
right? The United States, um, fiscally
is in a debt bubble. Um, and there's a
lot of debt that's been taken out to pay
for AI. And so you've got
some concerns around what interest rates
are going to do. And so I think you've
got a lot of people freaked out about
the levels of debt that are swimming
around in the markets right now. Jordan,
I think what's more concerning to me is
the acceleration of model performance
and what is being rumored about the
models that are not yet publicly
released but already exist inside of
these labs right now. Not just in terms
of how dangerous they could
theoretically be or how they can be
leveraged by bad actors, but if we, you
know, very few people have been as pro-
AAI as I have, but the one concern is
that it moves too fast. We need time to
adjust. Companies need time to adjust.
Markets need time to adjust. And it's
starting to feel like everything is
moving so fast that it and by the way I
say they're moving. You know where
things are not moving fast? I went to
open house at my kids high school this
week and I sat through seven classes of
curriculum. And do you know what was not
discussed even one time? Artificial
intelligence. And this is one of the top
schools in the country right
>> guys. I can't even believe it. I was
sitting through these classes and they
were talking about curriculum that felt
like the 1970s and I was just listening
going, "Does anyone here know what the
hell is going on right now in the
world?" Because there's essentially not
one thing that's being taught that I
think is going to matter at all
>> in a year or two. Like I I'm just I'm
flabbergasted that we are still in a
society where we have tens of millions
of kids waking up every day where we
have a magic ball that if you can figure
out how to manipulate um this magic
ball, you could theoretically do
anything. You could cure diseases. You
could potentially even predict what
humans are going to do a year from now.
There are an infinite number of things
that we could do with this magic ball.
And yet we have the entirety of our
youth waking up every morning and going
to school
learning things like the magic ball
doesn't exist. It's
>> No, I don't agree with that, Chris. I
think look um and there there so
education is a science and it turns out
that we've been studying this for a long
time and any amount of screen time that
you give somebody um who's going through
education um
has a negative effect on how much they
learn. And if you want to teach somebody
AI, I think that's fine. I think it
needs to be segmented away from the
other topics and they need to actually
be able to sit down and learn because we
want to educate people. We don't want
them to just think that there's this
magic eightball out there that will
solve all problems.
It doesn't do good for human cognition.
And this is
>> I don't believe any of what you're
saying. I don't believe any I think that
is the
>> this isn't belief or not believe these
are things that have been like this is
this is
not science. It's not science. That's
pseudo. No, no. You're you're you're
either you or some other headline that
you read is in
>> No, no, no, no. This isn't a headline,
buddy. This is like I read books about
this.
>> I don't lend you the books and you can
read about what books that were written
when the last month
>> time in front of a screen and it's not
good.
>> We can agree that screen time isn't
good, but ignoring AI is a totally
different argument. This is screen time.
>> This is not screen time.
>> It is screen. It's 100% screen time.
>> Okay. That's like saying Jordan that
someone that was learning how to code at
age 16 is wasting their time because I
don't disagree. Right. So I'm saying
that it can be in one step. So you could
have like an AI class just like you'd
have a programming class and that they
could then do that. But I don't think it
should be all day every day that they're
just sitting on a computer interacting
with AI. It's not it's it's not good for
you. Now, I don't think that that's the
argument. It's not sitting around
interacting with AI. It is the fact that
the current curriculum at Chris's kids
school is ignoring the fact that AI even
exists and teaching 1950 style reading,
writing, and arithmetic without the even
thought that a calculator exists, right?
>> Yeah. Well, it turns out that using a
calculator or using a computer to to do
things instead of using like a pencil
and paper, it has a negative correlation
to academic success.
>> I I Okay, academic success. Well, hold
on. If you academic success is means
nothing. What does that even mean?
>> Yes, it does.
>> I I the measure should not be academic
success. The measure should be actual
real difference that's being made in the
physical world.
>> So academic success transfers to like
test scores and IQ and things like that
that um
>> I don't care about test scores and IQ.
What I care about
>> I do. Right. So when I want my kids in
school learning is actually how to
learn, right? And then they can then use
those skills to transfer to AI if they
ever want to interact or if they need to
interact with AI. But I want them in
school actually learning how to learn.
>> I think at age 16 they need to be
learning how to utilize the tools these
magical tool sets that have just become
available to humanity.
>> Yeah. And that's fine. They can learn
that in like a period, right? So they've
got like one of their classes they get
to learn how to use some of these more
up-to-date technologies. Everywhere else
I want them to have a pencil and paper.
>> Oh, I Oh, you are so
>> I'm dead serious about this. By the way,
I'll send you books. I will send you
like a stack of books.
>> Books don't matter anymore. They were
written so I don't know. You know, years
ago,
>> there's been no time that I'm happier
that I do not have kids and I don't have
any of this to worry about. Li listen I
I I just there's never been a point in
history where you could do so much right
if you simply
understand how to leverage tool sets
right and I think there's a tremendous
amount of learning and and a lot of very
difficult brain processing that is
involved with understanding how to
manipulate ate artificial intelligence,
how to leverage artificial intelligence,
how to utilize the tools to solve real
problems. Okay? And so life is about
problem solving. And yet these kids are
not learning how to solve problems.
Listen,
>> no, they are learning how to solve
problems and they're learning language
and they're learning arithmetic and
they're learning these things that are
very important for children to learn.
And just because they're not doing it
with AI and having AI do it doesn't mean
that they're not learning. I think that
they should be able to have access to
these tools, but it needs to be limited.
Very limited.
>> Again, I'm talking about 16 year olds,
okay? Like
>> I'm also I'm talking about up through
college. I'm talking about everyone. I
think it's a I think it's I mean,
I know it's a huge problem that we're
shoving computers in front of these
kids.
>> Their ability to learn. Chris,
>> this is this is this is not up for this
isn't a debate, right? I think it's a
debate.
>> It's not a debate. It's not a debate at
all. I will like I but I actually study
this stuff. I I know that you don't.
>> I I just I'm not to tell you that I've
studied it as much as you have. I
haven't. Okay. I'll admit that right
now. But intuitively, it just doesn't
make any sense to me. And I'm going to
go right back to myself.
>> Intuition a lot of times the best way to
attack a problem.
>> I'm going to go right back to myself.
Okay.
>> Yeah. Basically, the entirety of my
college education was literally BS and I
didn't pay attention to any of it. And
thank God I didn't because I went on to
actually build companies, build
products, change the world, do a hundred
different things because I didn't waste
my time studying that crap. Okay? And
that was preAI. Like it was a joke. I
was in college sitting in classes going,
"This is the biggest, dumbest thing I've
ever seen in my life." a complete
idiocracy waste of every one of our
>> who knows if the major that you were in
corresponded to what you actually wanted
to learn. I actually learned a ton from
my education in college. Um but we in my
in my classes we didn't use computers.
We had a pencil and paper and we were
doing uh mathematics like we were doing
differential equations and linear
algebra and all these things in class
and
>> they weren't using computers in computer
science. What's that?
>> They weren't using computers in computer
science.
>> Well, I didn't I didn't study computer
science. I was
>> Okay, but Jordan, let me just ask you a
question. Even leveraging AI itself, you
see, have you read the data on the AI
school in Austin, they're learning stuff
5x quicker when they're leveraging AI to
actually learn because it's
individualized and they're not using
pencil and paper. It's the AI teaching
these kids.
>> Sure. Yeah. I mean, I would love to see
the peer-reviewed study that shows what
they're actually doing with this and
figure out if it's real or not.
>> I mean, you can say that they're 5x
quicker or something. I I don't know. I
mean, I haven't looked at that.
Everything that I've read
>> says that you need to get screens away
from kids as much as possible.
>> It's propaganda the same way. It's not
>> the same way they said television was
going to melt our minds and video. Have
you seen all the information on video
games now? how they're saying that kids
that play video games are x amount
smarter and more capable and all this
stuff. They told us for years that video
games are going to melt our
minds and and that's
>> Yeah, video games are a little bit
different, right? Because there's a more
you're more interactive I I and you you
get some like spatial awareness things
with video games that I think you're not
going to get through interacting with a
prompt with AI. I think I think you can
make an argument on either side for
video games and have plenty of data to
show that video games have ruined
people's lives and video games have made
people faster and more nimble and better
able to think.
>> I'll just I'll just say I'll
>> I think we need to retire this because
there are people that are saying that
I'm right. There are people that are
saying that you're dumb or that you're
>> One closing thought. One closing
thought. I do think regardless of this
particular argument that we're having, I
think the entire nature of peerreed
studies and interpreting
these sorts of things I think is mostly
bogus from what I
>> So you're anti-science?
>> No, I'm not anti-science. What I'm tell
Listen, there's been a lot of talk, you
could read this right now. There's been
a lot of discussion recently about how
these peer-reviewed studies are
unbelievably biased. Unbelievably biased
based on the individual that is behind
the study, right? As opposed to the
information, the study itself.
I just his if you look historically on
this stuff and I'm not
it is so biased and so completely
manipulated by what people already want
to think. So they go out and perform
these studies. They go out and interpret
these studies in various ways. They get
reprinted. And a lot of what I'm I just
think it's BS. Like I don't
>> seems like an RFK Jinger type of
argument to me.
Well, well, because a lot of this you're
looking at acade you, if the measuring
stick is academic success, if the
measuring stick is stuff like that,
that's not a success point I even think
is valid. So, like I
>> So, is what is the success point though?
Is the success point how much money did
you make or
>> No, sometimes that's not necessarily
>> No, the success point the success point
is moving moving the needle of humanity.
That that's it. And and and if you take
two a control group and another group
and you have one group learning this old
way and you have another
>> that's not me like moving a needle in
humanity is not a a measurable
>> it absol I'm I'm saying that in a really
broad sense. I'm saying who could have
the most which group would have the most
impact the most positive impact on our
civilization during their lifetime.
Okay. How about that? How about that
being
>> but that's not that's again that's not
that's not a measurable thing. Right.
Okay. But even that even that is
difficult because you have someone like
an Elon Musk who has moved society more
than anyone else and people hate him on
both sides.
>> Okay. But Jordan, you can I I know this
that's the thing. It's you're right. It
is really difficult right now to have an
endpoint on something that's changing so
quickly because we need a lot of time.
We would need years and years and years.
So what I have to depend on is just my
intuitive sense. Yeah.
>> That I'm seeing what's available in the
world to use. And if I were to take a
group of 20 kids and have them do what
I'm seeing in this school as opposed to
actually out there like these kids that
I've spent time with personally at Alpha
School in Austin. I spent time with them
in Hawaii. They I did the whole shark.
These kids are operating like 30 year
olds. Okay.
interesting to see in 20 30 years what
those alpha kids did versus the kids at
Highland Park to see what is that
outcome.
>> We we won't know for a long time. And by
the way, I'm not ripping on these
schools because I just think they don't
they're not in our situation. No, I
think I think that I think that there is
science around like and it's not just
mathematics, but it's also writing and
reading that if you use a keyboard to
write, you don't learn language as well
as you do when you use a pencil and
paper, right? So that's that's that's
settled science, right? So the condition
that you get out of using a pencil and
paper to write down your thoughts,
>> you develop the ability to read and
write better than you do.
>> But does that end point matter anymore?
>> The way that like the ability to
understand other people. This is the
ability to understand language is you
get way more out of using a pencil and
paper than you do using a keyboard. This
is okay.
>> This is studies. There are studies that
have been done since the 70s about
>> doesn't matter anymore is
>> it does matter. The ability to
understand people in language is a huge
>> if you don't think if you don't think
it's important to understand language I
I don't know what to tell you.
>> I mean I have four different bots
reading my emails right now for me so
that I don't have to. And then they just
they just give me a capsule summary of
the things
>> and you have no idea what's going on.
Right. So that's that's fine. What if
the thing that matters, Jordan,
30 years from now is just like something
that has nothing to do with any of that?
What What if all that matters is sports?
>> I look I What if all that matters is
sports?
>> That's But that's not all that matters
for everyone. That might be all for
somebody that cares about fantasy
football, but for me, I don't care about
fantasy football. I'm in a league. I
have fun with it. But what I care about
is reading books and understanding and
trying to expand my knowledge.
>> My my favorite comment so far is uh
Jordan just went long Barnes & Noble.
Saw that in the chat.
>> What if long Amazon? That's what started
out as a retailer. But but do you do you
do realize that if you move back 50 60
70 years people the things that they
thought would be important for education
today like in today's world what's
important
>> that's a very blanket odd statement and
you haven't pro provided anything
concrete
>> hold on hold on today today what what is
is starting to be exceptionally
important the last few years quite
honestly is being charismatic enough to
be some content creator that's
makingundred hundreds of thousands of
dollars and there's millions of them by
the way. Millions and millions.
>> To be charismatic, you need to
understand humans and have cognition and
understand language. Well,
>> I listen, not necessarily. Maybe
>> look, everybody that I know that's very
charismatic, like you're charismatic,
Len is charismatic, like a ton of our
friends are charismatic, but you're also
like smart people. And I and I know that
you grew up using a pencil and paper to
write compositions and you were reading
books. Um, and all of the things that I
think are and not only that I think but
that have been shown to be very
important.
>> I would
>> don't discount the way that you learned
to get you where you are. Chris,
>> I didn't learn much. Yes, you did. Yes,
you finished school, dude. I I barely
got through school. I was I was I was
not even really My head wasn't even
there.
>> All right, everybody's over this.
Everybody
>> All right, fine. Sorry. I just I
>> That's all people keep saying. And uh
what does this have to do with trading?
Asking for a friend.
>> I don't know. I I I
>> I think this is a great debate. I think
that our clip editor is going to have a
real nightmare getting this down to 30
seconds. Five.
>> By the way, this is this is Chris and
Mai's love language is yelling at each
other.
>> Yeah.
>> Listen, all I'm all I'm saying is, you
know, you know, I'm all about, you know,
taking big swings in the market and all
this stuff. I I I am at a point right
now where I'm looking at what's
happening and what's coming out the next
few weeks and I have never been more
confused about how people are going to
interpret the information flow that's
going to hit us every day. So I would
advise investors to be really cautious
right now and and just not become
overconfident in how they think things
will play out in the short run because
we are living in a time of anomalies
right now. And while you can have a
really strong thesis and high conviction
in like the AI infrastructure trade or
the efficiency wave that's coming that I
believe will benefit companies like
Amazon, all this stuff. I think it's
really difficult to assess dayto day,
week to week, how people are going to
interpret the news flow that is coming.
And so I would just advise investors,
even me, I'm taking a little bit of a
step back right now and trying to keep
my leverage under control. So I just I
just wanted to share that. I do think
there's one thing I'd like to address
really quick and it's the Muse versus
Amazon uh story because this this is
something that I've spent a lot of time
on this week as a large Amazon holder
trying to assess the degree that Muse
and Agentic AI generally is going to be
a net positive or a net Amazon for
Amazon. It seems obvious to me that on
the infrastructure side, Agentic AI will
be
>> maybe the largest positive we've ever
seen since the birth of AI for
infrastructure companies because agents
are going to consume massive amounts of
compute doing simultaneous
uh you know uh runs of tokens. At the
same time, you can make a case. I'm not
sure that that this case is correct, but
you can make a case that agentic AI
could demolish the advertising layer as
we know it that we've been that that has
become such a big piece of Amazon's
earnings, right?
>> So, I don't know how long that would
take. I don't know if it's even going to
matter because they will make up for
that times two or three with
infrastructure spend over that time and
I don't believe any of this is going to
happen quickly honestly.
>> No, I don't think it's quick. And I
think that eventually we are going to
see a shift where agents are doing more
for people in making purchase decisions
and and actually doing transactions. But
I don't think that's going to happen
quickly. And I think that Amazon will
have a chance to figure out is there an
agentto agent advertising model? Is
there a way that you know the people
selling the products still want to get
their products in front of people? And
is there going to be some kind of gating
or or preferential treatment towards uh
paid for products? I I just think Amazon
still has a chance to figure out how
that's going to work. And we know
Amazon's also working on their own
agentic uh broad uh broad knowledge bots
to to improve uh what's their there's
called
>> Alexa. Yeah. Yeah. What is that called?
I was talking to you about that earlier
this week. Dave, Amazon is working on
its own muse that they want to integrate
into Alexa.
>> Well, they've got that, but they're the
only one of these u are they the only
one that are creating their own chips,
right? And so they're not beholdened to
um you know some of the
some of the purchases that other
companies are making um to an Nvidia or
to some of these other companies because
they're doing their own chip design.
>> No, you're right. It's project Okay, so
Amazon has project moonraker. That's the
internal code name for a full agentic
version of Alexa plus designed to
execute complex multi-step tasks from a
single request. So essentially Amazon is
going to have its own muse. Okay. And
they have more shopper data than anyone
in the world. I I I see that as being
really interesting. We'll see when that
product actually releases and their
ability to execute on that product. But
don't you see there being a day in the
next so many months where we have 10
products like Muse and every tech
company has their version of Muse that
they're pushing on the world
>> which is a nightmare because I already
am using four products like Muse and I
can't remember which one I started to
have a conversation with. Someone needs
to make a connector so that it can keep
them all in sync on their knowledge
about me so that when I have a conver I
start talking to Gemini about something
and then I have to copy and paste that
over to Chat GPT because they're going
to actually walk me through how to do
something. It's it's too much right now.
It's too much. I have four, like I said,
I have four different
>> agentic
uh personal assistants reading my email
right now. Each one of them flagging
different things. Oh, by the way, we
think that uh or Google just sent a
security alert that you've granted chat
GPT access. Is that
>> Hold on. You're you're granting these
things access to your email.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. Just just my my email.
>> I'm I'm petrified to do that. I actually
connected
>> I allowed
>> I'm doing that.
>> I allowed Muse to connect just to uh
like my DMs and stuff inside of
Instagram. And even then, I think it got
me in trouble with Instagram, even
though it's the same company, and I
couldn't reply to anyone's DMs, so they
shut me down for a week.
>> No,
D,
I have I have multiple agents watching
my email, flagging different things for
different reasons. I can't figure out
the logic behind who's doing what, but I
need someone to make them all talk to
each other, or I just need one to
actually win this battle. And I would I
would personally prefer it be Apple so
that it can all be done on device and
not in the cloud and and private cloud
compute when it needs to be because I
think Siri being able to read my Apple
mail and my iMessage those are the those
are the main communication channels. My
Gmail is just the the address that I
give to companies.
>> Yeah. But right now all that it does is
just summarization. Right. Siri
>> Oh no, it does it does a lot. the new
Siri once you update to the uh iOS 27,
it actually does a lot. You you can be,
you know, whatever whatever's on your
screen, you can say, "Hey, put this on
my calendar." Uh it
>> I just said the keyword, my phone lit
up. I'm like, "Oh my gosh."
>> But he here's here's the issue that
investors are happening. You could look
at Agentic Shopping, which is certainly
coming. You you can't avoid it. Agentic
shopping is going to be huge. Then you
look at a company like Shopify, and they
seem to be an obvious beneficiary of
Agentic Shopping. But now that we're in
the age of AGI and ASI,
do we even need a Shopify? Because will
there not be a clone of Shopify that
pops up within each of these agents that
that they control their own Shopify? Why
would they want to share with Shopify?
Right? So it's like when you think about
this really deeply, it gets really
difficult to discern where the value is
going to fall in an age of agentic
shopping. What will get disrupted? Who
will benefit? Um obviously consumers
benefit.
Guys, it's mindboggling. It it it's
really difficult and this is why you see
stocks acting so erratically daytoday
because there are a lot of opinions and
we just do not have the final answer on
this. We don't and and companies like
Bloom Energy I think are doing as well
as they are because they sit so far
upstream from all this stuff that
they're just they're just going to there
is energy. We don't have to worry about,
you know,
>> the world's going to continue to need
electricity to power this stuff
regardless of who whose stuff needs to
be powered most,
>> which puts us all the way back in
Jordan's energy episode that we should
do next week because like it's that's
the one thing that does not feel as
confusing.
>> Uh Chris, we we just got an alert from
the audience that you failed to uh post
this on X and I failed to remind you to
post it on X.
>> Oh, thank you guys. I I'll do it now.
Although it's
>> although we're Are we wrapping up? We're
like almost an hour into this now.
>> I'm still gonna do it.
>> That's some That's just really bad
management on your part. Why is Muse not
watching this for you and have a standby
uh if you forget to do it within the
first two minutes of the show? It just
doesn't work.
>> Or it should just do it for you no
matter what
>> because
>> Yeah, it should just do it for you.
There's no there's no downside. and it
got me in trouble with its own company.
>> You know, I was doing limited stuff with
it.
>> Muse should have a a Sentinel that is
watching everything that your Muse is
doing. And any anything that it's going
to do on your behalf, you you have to
approve. Did you somehow accidentally
approve everything when you weren't
paying attention?
>> No, I approved it responding to one
singular DM. That was it. And
>> it took that as reply to my DMs. I I
think the issue might have been that it
was scraping the DMs every 15 minutes,
but you think the company is owned by
Meta
>> and they don't even care.
>> Well, it doesn't matter.
>> WhatsApp is also owned by Meta and I
cannot get a reliable way for my news to
read my WhatsApp and I hate using
WhatsApp. It's what people in Mexico use
and I want it to be watching that to see
if anyone needs to reach me and then
just let me know on a channel use. It's
awful.
But they don't have a they don't have a
an agent. They don't have a way to log
in. You you can you basically are
logging in through like the web version.
And uh Muse doesn't have it. While Muse
does have a virtual computer for you,
it's not a persistent browser session.
And so it it loses the connection.
My Muse and I worked back and forth on
that for about three days and then we
just gave up.
>> The the the point I was trying to get
across is I've been investing for a
multitude of decades. Nothing
nothing really shakes me. And this is
one of the only times that I felt just
uncertain dayto day having being
completely clueless what's what I'm
going to wake up to in the morning. And
this is every single day and how other
investors are going to react to it. We
are in volatile times. We're in fragile
times. The world is changing too quickly
and it's unsettling and it makes it
really difficult to be an investor right
now and I just want to share that with
the community because I I would have to
imagine that other people are freaking
out and they're unsettled and they have
high anxiety and they're not alone. I
mean for me to feel this way means that
this is a weird ass market. This is a
weird ass world.
I wish it man I wish stuff would slow
down dude. I know it's not going to it's
I have to like
remove myself.
>> Yeah. What do you mean? So, you're
trying to say there's just too much
going on because it's not just AI that's
going on. We've got civil unrest going
on. We've got military operations going
on. We've got debt issues. We've got we
just got have a lot going on.
>> Jordan, that other stuff is really
important. Don't get me wrong, but I
feel that the AI is the thing that's
freaking me out dayto day because it's
accelerating and there's just unknowns
and there's not really a president for
it. So, we don't really
>> we don't and I don't feel that anyone
really understands it enough to like
there's no regulating it cuz who's going
to regulate it, right? We don't have
people that have competence to regulate.
>> Can you imagine?
>> Yeah, that's the biggest problem, right?
The government to regulate AI. I mean
they can barely regulate
>> the AI companies want the government to
do it just so that they have you know
they can say we've played within the
rules because because there are rules
right now there are no rules it's just
people doing whatever they want the AI's
just kind of running out of control. I I
agree that it is coming so fast and even
keeping up with it even even having your
AI summarize what happened over the past
24 hours
>> like we're we're now trusting AI to do
the summarization of what's going on
because it's all coming at us so fast
and there's no way you could possibly
even read the headlines of all of the
random breakthroughs and changes in the
technology overnight. It's it's too much
too fast.
>> Yeah, I can My long-term thesis hasn't
changed. I I love Amazon more every day.
I I am somewhat concerned about Agentic
Shopping being a net negative only for
the advertising division of Amazon and
being a net positive for every other
piece of Amazon.
Listen guys,
that said, I mean, you can see the
compute prices uh going up still week
over week. And this is all a net
positive for the one thing that matters
more than anything else at Amazon, of
course, which is AWS, Bedrock,
Gravitron, uh, Tranium, Chip Division,
like that. That's what's moving the
needle for Amazon and it's all a big
positive. And if we do inch closer to an
anthropic IPO that is anything close to
two trillion and by the way just about
everything that everyone's saying about
anthropic right now on X is wrong. It's
just clearly wrong. People are
misinterpreting
the filing. You know, they're like, "Oh,
they're going to spend half a trillion
this year on on No, they're not. That's
like over 10 years." Like everything
they're saying is wrong. they've lost
this much money. No, they didn't. It's
an accounting error. I not an
accounting, it's a it's an accounting
shift that that they did. So, it's just
so annoying. Like, I I tweeted this last
night. We've never had access to more so
much information and yet have spent so
little time actually analyzing it before
we have these strong dumb opinions.
Like, everyone
>> there's a race to have the opinion first
on X.
>> Yeah. and AI spitting out opinions on
people's behalf like mine which which
will end this week as soon as
>> maybe we should place more emphasis on
human cognition.
I I I mean listen you you know you know
Amazon's going to knock it out of the
park with with their AWS. Uh, you know,
there's probably going to be a a little
concern around the diesel prices and
shipping. Uh, Amazon probably took a hit
there this quarter. That's a net
negative. I think that the management
team is going to have plenty of time to
address aic shopping. They've probably
been thinking about it. They have an
answer for it. I would assume they will
tackle that issue on the next earnings
call. So when I run all my scenarios on
what the Amazon earnings call how it
might play out as of today, I feel
pretty bullish on it. But between now
and then, who the hell knows, man, this
market,
>> dude, let's not get overconfident. If
you're if you're investing with leverage
right now, that is
too much. Be careful, right? Like if
you're overconfident, you should not be
overconfident on anything in the short
run. days to weeks right now. Be
careful, guys. I just want to leave
people with that. And I rarely say that,
but I would say be careful right now.
That's all.
>> Words of wisdom.
>> I'm going to cap this under an hour.
That'd be that'd be
>> Yeah, I think I think we've done it.
>> All right.
>> Yeah, we have nothing else to say.
>> Awesome.
>> Except for I see the uh the tweet here.
Jordan wins.
>> Some people think so, some people think
Chris wins. No, I know. It's a It's a
pretty You watch the episode. Everybody
wins.
>> No, no. I I'll say this. I actually
really enjoy the debate. I think it's an
important debate that needs to be had.
Now, I didn't really do my homework to
to be able to properly debate Jordan
today. But I think it's a really
important debate because listen, the
future Well, I was going to say the
future are children, but do they even
matter anymore in an age of AI? I don't
even know.
I don't even know. They might not be the
future. The future might just be the
next frontier model. We don't The kids
just might be playing sports and telling
jokes and making stupid content for a
living. Like that could be the future.
>> That is the future.
>> It's a weird future. We're heading We're
We're barreling towards that weird weird
future. But we'll be there for you.
>> I'll I'll lean towards educating my
kids.
I'll I want them to be educated. I'm
just going to redefine what that
education means. I just don't know what
that word means right now.
>> I I don't think educators do. I think
that that the educators got so scared of
like people writing their papers using
AI that they're just like, well, we we
don't want to have any AI in the
classroom because we're afraid people
are going to use it to cheat. And now
>> I do think that that has been a problem,
Dave. I do think that's been a problem.
But there's there's so many studies that
show and there are school districts that
are doing the opposite of what Chris is
saying about the AI Academy and they're
getting rid of these, you know,
everybody gets a laptop type thing and
we're going to do all of our um
coursework on the laptop
because they've seen the studies and
they know that cognition drops as you
use and you lean on uh screen time more
and more. And we're gonna have to get to
the end to the bottom of this to see.
>> It doesn't matter what you think. It's
it's they've they've done studies on
this.
>> You can think whatever you want. It's a
free country
>> studies.
>> They've done studies that have been
published by books.
>> All right, we're done, Money. Thanks for
watching. We'll see you guys uh maybe
maybe another one this week, but you you
know we are not going to do that. We'll
see you next
That's
here.